Berkley Olmstead

5531 S. Adonis, Boise, ID 83716 | 208-871-3882 olms2074@gmail.com | www.berklevolmstead.com | github.com/Bolmstead

Summary

Software developer with experience creating Full-Stack web applications, building and communicating with REST and SOAP API's, and developing logic to communicate with SQL and MongoDB databases. Currently working as a Full-Stack developer building a CRM website application to be used by several trucking companies.

Skills

Languages, Frameworks, and Libraries: Javascript, Python, React, Redux, Node.JS, Node Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, PostgreSQL, SQL, Sequelize, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Less.JS, Node-pg, Flask, SQLAlchemy, AJAX, Axios, JWTs, Figma, Material-UI, Ant Design, Bootstrap

Other Tools and Skills: REST API Development, MongoDB & SQL Database Schema Design, Netlify & Heroku Deployment, Git, Github, Communicating with REST and SOAP APIs, Web-scraping, NFT Development

Experience

TEKware - Remote Position

August 2021 - Present

Senior Full-Stack Software Developer

- Built a React website page UI and the necessary Node backend models, routes, and controllers to allow trucking managers to create, edit, delete, and query tasks for their employees.
- Fully integrated the Qwest SOAP API into our code base to allow managers to issue randomized drug tests.
- Developed the backend models & REST API routes, frontend UI, and MongoDB schema with various M2M relationships to let managers create, edit, and delete tractor and trailer assignments to certain drivers.
- Utilized and refined the following skills working on this project: React, Redux, Node.JS, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, REST API route creation, SOAP/REST external API communication, Ant Design, Git, and Github.

Idaho State Tax Commission - Boise, ID

February 2016 - March 2020

Tax Auditor

- Investigated non-filing taxpayer income and tax documents to establish their domicile status.
- Calculated state individual tax deficiencies and prepared audit findings defending my position.
- Handled over 200 audits simultaneously, increasing the state's income by over \$80,000 a year on average.
- Met with taxpayers to communicate tax code ambiguities guiding them to an appropriate plan of action.

Projects

FreeBay Website

February 2021 - Present

- Developed a full-stack product bidding website using React, Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL.
- Created a UI using CSS and Material UI allowing users to search for products, view users profiles that displays their bids/products won, and a homepage showing the most recent bids and products won.
- Built the <u>backend and API</u> with Node.JS, Node-PG, and Express that contains REST routes that: supply a JWT upon validation, query product data, post bids, and updates the database when an auction is over.
- Created SQL database schema with multiple relational tables and deployed the API with Heroku.

Education

Springboard Software Engineering Career Track

Completion Date: April 2021

- 800+ hours of hands-on online course material, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects.
- Refined skills in front-end and back-end web development, databases, and data structures & algorithms.

University of Idaho- College of Business and Economics - *Moscow, ID* B.S. in Business, Accounting and Finance - *Cumulative GPA: 3.45*

Degrees Received: December 2012

Certified Public Accountant Exam - Passed all 4 sections of exam